Guide to the New-York Historical Society Poster Collection 1790-2022 PR 55
New-York Historical Society
- Series IX. Other Subjects, 1896-2021
  - Subseries IX.1. Chronological, 1896-2021
    - Van Cortlandt House Museum, undated (Folder FF 09-01)
      Admission times and the further information that admission was free except on Thursdays when a 25 cent fee covered afternoon tea in the Colonial Kitchen. Poster signed by F.L.V.H.
    - The Art Directors Club of New York's first Dinner Meeting of the Season informational poster, 1930 (Folder FF 09-02)
      Russel Crouse was scheduled to speak on his recently published book, "Mr. Currier and Mr. Ives" at the Hotel Martinique on Friday, Dec. 19, 1930. "Engravings by Knapp. Typography by Schmidt & Lepiz. Printing contributed by Kenilworth Press." On back, in pen, "Gift of Eugenia Maurer Fuerstenberg (daughter of Louis Maurer) June 30, 1939".
    - The United States Army Recruiting Service Recruitment Poster, 1931 (Folder FF 09-02)
      Poster features portrait of George Washington on a horse with the words: "First in War, First in Peace, First the Hearts of His Countrymen -". Aquisition date (?) on back: Feb. 17, 1932.
    - Washington Headquarters, Morristown, N.J., Washington Bi-Centennial Celebration, 1932 (Folder FF 09-02)
      Celebration scheduled for July 4-5th at the Washington Headquarters in Morristown.
    - Unemployed Council of Greater New York Grand Parade and Mass Meeting against the "Block-Aid System", 1932 (Folder FF 09-02)
      H. Benjamin, National Secretary of Unemployed Councils, U.S.A., and Carl Winter, Secretary of Greater New York Council, were to speak at the parade and meeting to urge workers to unite and demand cash relief and unemployment insurance. On front, in pencil, "Gift of Mr. E.B. Child. May 23, 1934".
    - The International Labor Defense Demonstration Against War and Fascism., 1934 (Folder FF 09-02)
      March held on Aug. 4, 1934 from Columbus Circle to Madison Square. "Join our ranks (International Labor Defense)... to learn the Truth about Strikes and Labor Struggles." On back, in pencil, "July 28, 1934".
    - "Scenes from the Living Theatre - No. 1 Masses and Men", 1934 (Folder FF 09-02)
      Montage of photos by Film Photo League. Photos of poverty and protests on social and economic issues. On back, in pencil, "Communist Movement, N.Y. Spring 1934"
    - The American Museum of Natural History Lecture Series for Members, 1935 (Folder FF 09-05)
      Lectures included one on the new planetarium and one on the Conquest of Everest.
    - The American Museum of Natural History Lecture Series for Children of Members, 1935 (Folder FF 09-05)
      Children's lectures included Exploring under the Sea and Arctic Adventures.
    - "Save Lives Through Safe Habits. Works Progress Administration", 1936 (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster designed by I.L.S. On front, in pencil, "W.P.A. Placard on public school building, 132 W. 55th St." On back, in pencil, "Gift of Mrs. George Wilde. Nov. 19, 1936".
    - F.B.I. $10,000 Reward Post about kidnapping and murder of Charles Fletcher Mattson of Tacoma, Washington., 1937 (Folder FF 09-05)
      Kidnapping occurred on December 27, 1936 and reward for information posted on January 12, 1937 by John Edgar Hoover, Director of the F.B.I. Acquisition date (?) on back: May 7, 1946.
    - Advertisement for "The Village Fair. Washington Mews, Just South of No. 1 Fifth Ave.", 1938 (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster drawn by Hirschfeld. The Fair was held to benefit the Spanish Children's Milk Fund, Auspices Women's Division Medical Bureau, and the North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy. On back, in pencil, "Gift of H.B. Hoffman. July 15, 1938."
    - Printing & Allied Industries 5th Educational Graphic Arts Exposition, 1939 (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster designed by Goring. Exposition held at the Grand Central Palace. There are also stamps with the same graphics. Acquisition date (?) on back: Aug. 4, 1939.
    - "Ernest Dudley Chase Pictorial Maps Price $1.00 each" Advertisement, 1939 (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster copyrighted by Ernest Dudley Chase, Boston, Massachusetts. Along with the poster is a smaller pamphlet with a further description of the pictorial maps which include maps of France, Germany, Spain and Portugal, British Isles, Boston, Manhattan, and the United States, among others. Poster was folded and sent to the New-York Historical Society, postmarked 1939 from Boston. Sent by "Beautiful Pictorial Maps by Ernest Dudley Chase".
    - New York City W.P.A. Historical Records Survey Informational Sessions, [1940] (Folder FF 09-02)
      "This work pays your community" "Is doing for your community ... Guide to depositories manuscript collections...Old town record transcriptions...American Imprints Inventory...Inventory of the church archives in New York City...Inventory of City County and Borough archives of New York City". 2 copies. On back, in pencil, on both copies, "May 31, 1940".
    - "Printing Bulwark of Liberty 1440-1940" (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster printed by the International Association of Printing House Craftsmen to celebrate the 500th anniversary of the Invention of Printing. Acquisition date (?) on back: Oct. 21, 1940.
    - "Printing Ink Makes People Think. 500th Anniversary of the Invention of Printing, 1940." (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster printed by the International Association of Printing House Craftsmen in cooperation with the National Association of Printing Ink Makers. Acquisition date (?) on back: Oct. 21, 1940.
    - "500th Anniversary of the Invention of Printing 1440-1940. Signalizing the Service of Printing to the Community" (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster printed by the Interantional Association of Printing House Craftsmen. Acquisition date (?) on back: Oct. 21, 1940.
    - The Cuneo Press, Inc. Display Sheet at the 1940 World's Fair in New York (Folder FF 09-05)
      The Display Sheet is a "page from the Sermon on the Mount...set in the reconstructed Donat type, the first known movable type (1440), and...printed on a replica of the Gutenberg press exhibited by The Cuneo Press, Inc. in celebration of 500 years of printing at the World's Fair of 1940 in New York." Acquisition date (?) on back: Oct. 14, 1941.
    - Advertisement for The Old Fort Niagara, c. 1940 (Folder FF 09-02)
      The advertisement which included a space for folders to takeaway, was copyrighted by Old Fort Niagara Association, Inc. and executed by N.Y. State Art Project W.P.A.. On front, in pencil, 1940. Aquisition date (?) on back: July 2, 1940.
    - "Unification - June 12, 1940" (I.R.T. and Mayor of New York City) (Folder FF 09-05)
      The Interborough Rapid Transit Company's The Elevated Express Vol. XII, No. 22. Printed by The Ma(...)hbanks Press, New York. Designed by Fred Cooper. Acquisition date (?) on back: June 13, 1940.
    - The Artists Guild Moonlight Sail, 1940 (Folder FF 09-05)
      The Moonlight Sail was on Wednesday, July 17th, on the palatial river steamer, S.S. Mayflower, leaving from the foot of Battery Place. Stamped date of Nov 3 1944 on front. Note on back, in pencil, "Recv July 9/40" and stamped, "Please Post".
    - "It's Here! It's Great!! It's the Real Thing!!! which means Super-entertainment!!" (Committee for Peace), 1940 (Folder FF 09-05)
      The event was on Oct. 5, 1940 at 79 E. 10th St. and Woody on guitar was part of the entertainment. Acquisition date (?) on back: Nov. 4, 1941.
    - "Use Water Wisely!!!" (Department of Water Supply, Gas and Electricity)., 1941 (Folder FF 09-05)
      New York City reservoirs only 1/3 filled because of drought. LaGuardia was Mayor and Patrick Quilty was Commissioner of the Department of Water Supply. Acquisition date (?) on back: Dec. 16, 1941.
    - The Nordacs Club, Inc. 23rd Annual Gala All Star Show and Dance., 1941 (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster printed by Allied Printers of New York and approved by Theater Authority, Inc. The Show and Dance was for the benefit of the Welfare Fund and held at the Manhattan Center with music by Sammy Wilson & his orchestra. Acquisition date (?) on back: Nov. 4, 1941.
    - "Stop Needless Noise. Help America Keep Calm" (Police Department City of New York, Safety Program), [1942] (Folder FF 09-02)
      2 copies. Poster designed by Howard Scott. Contribution by National Noise Abatement Council and F.H. La Guardia, Mayor.
    - "Book Week", 1942 (Folder FF 09-05)
      "Forward with Books" slogan. November 15th-21st. Acquisition date (?) on back: Nov. 9, 1942.
    - "These are the Times ...." December 1942. (Oscar Hayman Fabrics of Fashionation) (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster printed by Alvin Gardner Co., advertising. Features portrait of and quote by Thomas Paine. Also quote by Oscar Hayman referencing "turning point of a great war." Acquisition date (?) on back: Dec. 16, 1942.
    - Sociedades Hispanas Confederadas conmemora el 19 de Julio, 1943 (Folder FF 09-02)
      The commemoration of Spanish heriocs and sacrifice was held at The Manhattan Center on 34th Street. Noted at the bottom was the radio station to hear the Voice of Sociedades Hispanas Confederadas every day but Sundays from 9:30 -10:00 p.m. Aquisition date (?) on back: Sept. 12, 1944.
    - Supplement to Woman's Day Magazine's Christmas issue of 1945 (Folder FF 09-05)
      "Reprinted from Woman's Day, The A&P Magazine. Copyright, 1946, by Stores Publishing Company, Inc." Attached note from Woman's Day magazine explains that Olin Downes, authority on music, chose masterpieces of grand opera from which the most remembered scenes have been drawn by John Held, Jr. The chart was reproduced from the Woman's Day Christmas issue. Acquisition date (?) on back: Dec. 5, 1945.
    - Noche Atomica Grand Ball with 2 Orchestras -- Marcelino Guerra with Ayala on piano and Montesino and his rhythm set, 1946 (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster printed by Manhattan Press. The grand ball took place on Saturday, January 26th, at the Hunt's Point Palace. On back, in pencil, "Feb. 1, 1946. Gift of Henry B. Hoffmann."
    - Income Tax Return Filing Reminder, 1946 (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster printed by the U.S. Government Printing Office. Reminder that if income was $500 or more, need to file tax return with District Collector of Internal Revenue by March 15th. Acquisition date (?) on back: April 30, 1946.
    - Supplement to Woman's Day Magazine's April issue of 1946 (Folder FF 09-05)
      "Reprinted from Woman's Day, The A&P Magazine. Copyright, 1946, by Stores Publishing Company, Inc." Attached note from Woman's Day Magazine explains that the chart depicts paintings of great masters compiled by Thomas Craven and laid-out by George Salter. Reproduced from the April issue. Acquisition date (?) on back: April 1, 1946.
    - Pennsylvania Railroad Strike Warning Poster, [1946] (Folder FF 09-02)
      Alert that the railworkers were scheduled to strike at 4:00 p.m. on Saturday, May 18th.
    - Philipse Castle Restoration 3rd Birthday Celebration (Sleepy Hollow), 1946 (Folder FF 09-02)
      Celebration took place on July 4, 1946. Included a restored Headless Horseman Bridge and advertised as Greater New York's most amazing garden spot. Aquisition date (?) on back: June 14, 1946.
    - Advertisement for U.S. Savings Bonds, 1946 (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster printed by the Government Printing Office. "Official U.S. Treasury Poster SBD 77A". Aquisition date (?) on back: June 17, 1946.
    - "Happy Birthday Pennsy. One hundred years of Transportation Progress." (Pennsylvania Railroad & New York City Transit System), 1946 (Folder FF 09-05)
      The Subway Sun, Vol. XIII, No. 9. Designed by OPPY. Acquisition date (?) on back: May 31, 1946.
    - U.S. Frigate Constitution (Old Ironsides) 150 Birthday Celebration, 1947 (Folder FF 09-02)
      Poster was printed by Patrick J. Connelly, Postmaster of Boston 9, Massachusetts. The celebration exercises were conducted by Robert E. Hannegan, Postmaster General, and included the introduction of a commemorative stamp. Aquisition date (?) on back: Nov. 13, 1947.
    - Invitation to Visit The Tent (on the grounds of St. John the Divine Cathedral), undated (Folder FF 09-02)
      The Tent was open every night except Saturday for singing. On back, in pencil, "E.B. Child/39".
    - Sunday afternoon free concert series held at the Holyrood Church, undated (Folder FF 09-02)
      Silk screen print by School of Industrial Art. Holyrood Church is at the corner of 179 St. & Fort Washington Ave.
    - "Jubilate! The Glorious Fourth is now doubly glorious It sees the downfall of Militarism - So Rejoice: Jubilate!", [1919?] (Folder FF 09-04)
      Poster features an eagle image overlaid on a red, white, blue outline of the United States. At bottom, in corner, "C-29-C"
    - "Universite de Dijon, Cours de Francais" Advertisement [French], undated (Folder FF 09-04)
      Poster printed by Jobard. Dijon. Poster advertises french classes -- language, literature and history -- for foreign students for a summer or a full year.
    - 1950 Annual Campaign of the Greater New York Fund (Folder FF 09-06)
      Poster includes an alphabetized list of voluntary services helped by the campaign. On back, a printed request to post and a stamped date: Jun 26 1950.
    - "New Life for Youth" City-Wide Youth Rally advertisement, 1951 (Folder FF 09-06)
      Rally sponsored by the New Life Advance Committee of New York Presbytery and featured Jackie Robinson, Chuck Templeton, and Dr. John A. MacKay. It was held at Rutgers Presbyterian Church.
    - Advertisement for The State Insurance Fund Accident Reduction Contest, 1951 (Folder FF 09-06)
      Reason for contest: "National Security Demands Accident Prevention" Images of workers, the globe and New York State. Stamped on back: Feb 19 1951.
    - "Join Payroll Savings" Official U.S. Treasury Poster, 1951 (Folder FF 09-06)
      Poster printed by the U.S. Government Printing Office. Features baseball player, Ralph Kiner. Date stamped on back: Nov 7 1951.
    - "Join Payroll Savings" Official U.S. Treasury Poster, 1951 (Folder FF 09-06)
      Poster printed by the U.S. Government Printing Office. Features a solider with the slogan, "Defense is your job too!", and a $100 Series E U.S. Bond. Stamped date on back: Sep 28 1951.
    - The 1951 New York Antiques Fair advertisement (Folder FF 09-06)
      Poster printed bby T.J. Lyons Press. The Fair featured exhibits by members of the Art and Antique Dealers League of America. On back, stamped "Please Post" and "Nov 7 1951".
    - New York State Insurance Fund Christmas and New Year's Greeting, 1951 (Folder FF 09-06)
      Poster sponsored by The State Insurance Fund of the State of New York. Stamped on back: Feb 6 1952.
    - Buy Israel Bonds. Birthday Salute to the State of Israel., 1953 (Folder FF 09-02)
      The event which included appearances by many actors, musicians, and Israel and American leaders, including Senators Humphrey and Morse, was held at the RKO Fordham theater.
    - "be careful...Driving...Or On Foot avoid winter accidents", 1953 (Folder FF 09-06)
      Poster sponsored by Group Insurance Department, The Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States. Acquisition date (?) on back: January 15, 1953.
    - The 1955 New York Antiques Fair advertisement (Folder FF 09-06)
      The Fair was at the 71st Infantry Armory under Nuttall-Hazen Management. "Please Post" stamped on back.
    - Army Recruiting Office advertisement to "Enlist"., undated (Folder FF 09-05)
      2 copies. Poster printed by Byan & Hart Co. Printers, Chicago. Poster features an appeal for soliders by George Washington.
    - "For your safety, while New York sleeps, our men check your trains", 1956 (Folder FF 09-06)
      The New York City Transit Authority's The Subway Sun, Vol. 23, No. 13. On back, in pencil, "Oct-Nov. 1956. 207th Street Train Yards."
    - "Shop Now, Mail Early, Use Christmas Seals on all your Letters and Packages", 1957 (Folder FF 09-06)
      Poster printed by Malgamated Lithographers of America. Postmaster's important holiday reminders. Christmas Seals to fight Tuberculosis.
    - "National Foreign Language Week" advertisement, 1958 (Folder FF 09-06)
      Poster designed by Bruce Russell. Language Week sponsored by Alpha Nu Gamma National Foreign Language Society. Stamped on back: Jan 2 1976.
    - Notice of the International Longshoremen's Association Portwide Meeting, 1958 (Folder FF 09-06)
      Meeting to discuss "Automation in the Longshore Industry and What it Means to You". Open to Longshoremen, checkers, and allied crafts. "Attend and protect your job, your pension, your welfae benefits. At Madison Square Garden at 50th St. & 8th Ave. On back, in pencil, "Gift of Michael Staats - 1996".
    - Advertisement for Free Family Fallout Shelter Booklet from the Office of Civil and Defense Mobilization, 1959 (Folder FF 09-06)
      Poster printed by U.S. Government Printing Office and designed by Lee.
    - "Step up to the JobCorps. Men & Women - Age 16 to 21", ca 1965 (Folder FF 09-06)
      Poster features the ladder and up arrow logo. "Work, Learn, Earn away from home"
    - "Mollify them...quote Newsweek" advertisement, ca 1970 (Folder FF 09-06)
      Poster features a photograph of a female model with a gun next to a vintage Rolls Royce and the slogan, "the newsweekly that separates fact from opinion".
    - "City of New York Police Department Police Academy Combat Target", 1962 (Folder FF 09-06)
      Target used at New York Police Academy.
    - "Virginia Slims Women's Tennis Circuit", 1972 (Folder FF 09-07)
      Poster for a tournament held at the Newport Casino, Newport, R.I. for the benefit of the National Lawn Tennis Hall of Fame. Gift of Harley Spiller, 2022.
    - Tarrytown Fire Dept. Annual Bazaar, 1975 (Folder FF 09-07)
      Poster printed by Triangle Poster Co. Midway by B&B Ride Company. Acquisition date (?) stamped on back: Aug 5 1975.
    - "WANTED by the New York City Police Department HORSES...", 1976 (Folder FF 09-07)
      The poster was designed by Sgt. Michael Daly and printed by the City of New York Police Department. The police department was looking for donated horses for the mounted police, and, according to a note on the back, H.Ross Perot donated 20 horses. The note continues that the poster was "acquired for the Exhibition "New York on the Brink" Courtesy of Nick Muglia.
    - The Great New York State Children's Party, 1979 (Folder FF 09-07)
      Related Materials
      Poster designed by Doug Lapp. The Children's Party was held at Battery Park in New York City and sponsored by the Governor's (Hugh L. Carey) Commission on the International Year of the Child in cooperation with the New York City Department of Parks and Recreation (Gordon J. Davis, Commissioner).
    - Westbeth 10th Anniversary Celebration poster, 1980 (Folder FF 09-07)
      Poster designed by R.P. Sullivan and printed by ConEdison. Westbeth is an artists' community in the West Village.
    - "Britain Salutes New York 1983" (Folder FF 09-07)
      The event was sponsored by the New York International Arts Festival and celebrated the 200th year anniversary of the signing of the Treaty of Paris. Acquisition date (?) stamped on back: May 12 1983.
    - Third Annual Presidential Conference at Hofstra University Cultural Center, 1984 (Folder FF 09-07)
      The poster was designed by Francoise Gilot and features an image of Dwight D. Eisenhower, the Presidential Conference's focus that year. Alongside the large poster are two copies of a smaller poster featuring a photograph of Dwight D. Eisenhower, courtesy of Dwight D. Eisenhower Library. One copy is signed by "Susan Eisenhower", "Tex McCrary", and a third illegible signature. The other copy is stamped, "Approved for posting by the Office of Secretary". There is also 3 copied pages from the program booklet - the cover of the booklet and two pages, "About the Speakers". On the back of one copy of the small poster is the address of Susan Douglas.
    - Advertisement for the South Street Seaport Museum's Lamplight tour with the Ghost of Herman Melville, 1986 (Folder FF 09-07)
      Poster hand-set and printed at Bowne & Co., Stationers. Acquisition date (?) stamped on back: Dec 17 1986.
    - Daily News and NYC Police Department Public Service Announcement for a safer New York, 1988 (Folder FF 09-07)
      The poster is designed by George Sargent and Frank Henry. The poster is directed at children with the main idea to beware of strangers.
    - "1989-1990 Freedom Spreads..." (Folder FF 09-07)
      Poster printed by Matthews Marketing, Inc. under exclusive licensing rights from New York Times, Agence France-Presse, Bettman Reuters and Associated Press. Poster features a mock-up of a New York Times front page with headlines and photographs concerning freedom and democracy.
    - 21st New York City Marathon poster, 1990 (Folder FF 09-07)
      2 copies. Photograph on poster is credited to Duomo/David Madison. 1990 sponsors included Manufacturers Hanover, Mercedes-Benz, John Hancock, ASICS, The Rudin Family, and Runner's World.
    - Ground Breaking Ceremony for Eleanor Roosevelt Monument, 1993 (Folder FF 09-07)
      The poster features a photograph of the monument and the ground breaking was sponsored by the Eleanor Roosevelt Monument Fund and took place at Riverside Park and 72nd Street.
    - Reward poster for arrest and conviction of person who framed O.J., 1994 (Folder FF 09-07)
      Poster features mug shot of O.J. Simpson and offers a $500,000 reward for arrest and conviction of person or persons who framed O.J. In pencil on front, "Original - American Life Post".
    - "Indian Point - Safe. Secure. Vital", c.2001 (Folder FF 09-07)
      Poster by AmericanCampaignStore.com. Poster is folded in half lengthwise and stapled. Presumably it was used as a yard sign.
    - The 25th Annual Mermaid Parade at Coney Island, 2007 (Folder FF 09-08)
      Poster designed by Marc Kehoe and printed by Coney Island U.S.A. Sponsors of the parade included the Cyclones, Keyspan, Brooklyn Brewery, Taconic Investment Management, Astroland Amusement Park.
    - Centennial Commemoration of the Triangle Shirtwaist Factory Fire by Workers United/SEIU (ILGWU), 2011 (Folder FF 09-07)
      Poster printed by Allied Printers 515.
    - Celebrating Brooklyn Basketball, 2013 (Folder FF 09-08)
      Poster is officially licensed by Black Fives, Inc. and designed by Soular Creative. The Barclays Center honors the legacy of African-American Basketball in Brooklyn with the celebration to benefit the Back Fives Foundation.
    - "Justice for LGBTQ People is Justice for All", 2019 (Folder FF 09-08)
      The poster is done by the New York City Anti-Violent Project and printed on both sides, one in English, one in Spanish. Note with poster states it is a gift of Linda Ferber in 2019.
    - "Trust TGNC People, We Know What We Need", 2019 (Folder FF 09-08)
      Poster is done by the New York City Anti-Violence Project and is printed on both sides, one in English, one in Spanish. A note with the poster states that it is a gift of Linda Ferber in 2019.
    - National Poetry Month April 2021, Celebrating 25 years (Folder FF 09-08)
      Artwork is by Bao Lu. Lines excerpted from the poem "For Keeps" by Joy Harjo.
  - Subseries IX.2. Protests (incl 1982 Disarmament Rally), 1975-2018
    - "Let's Fight Back" Citywide Action Group Against Neighborhood Destruction and For Low-Rent Housing, 1975 (Folder FF 09-14)
      Poster "hand silk screened by Publicity and Propaganda - HOMEFRONT". Poster in both English and Spanish. Accompanying note explains poster. "Landlords As Rats" by Mimi Rosenberg, courtesy of the artist and acquired for the exhibition "New York on the Brink".
    - Protest to Close Live Animal Labs at the American Museum of Natural History, 1976 (Folder FF 09-14)